Guide to the John P. Marquand Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- John P. Marquand Papers, 1924-59; Series I; 15.25; (37 boxes)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Essays and Short Stories
      - "Cambodia"
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 660)
      - "Courtesy of the Port"
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 661)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 662)
        - Draft C, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 663)
      - Curzon's Mill, Article on
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 664)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 665)
        - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 666)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 667)
      - "Dear Old Golden Rule Days": draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 668)
      - "Deep Water": draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 669)
      - "Doctor's Orders"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1942 (Box 33, Folder 670)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, 1942 (Box 33, Folder 671)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, 1942 (Box 33, Folder 672)
      - "Federalist Newburyport, or Can Historical Fiction Remove a Fly from Amber?"
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, 1952 Jul 7 (Box 33, Folder 673)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, 1952 Jul 7 (Box 33, Folder 674)
      - "The General"
        - Draft A, typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 675)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 676)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 677)
      - "Golden Lads"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 678)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 679)
      - "Goodbye, Piccadilly"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 680-81)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 682)
      - "High Tide": draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 683)
      - "Keep the Cash": draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 684)
      - "King of the Sea"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1954 (Box 33, Folder 685)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1954 (Box 33, Folder 686)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, 1954 (Box 33, Folder 687)
        - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 33, Folder 688)
      - "Lunch at Honolulu"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1945 Apr 3 (Box 33, Folder 689)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, 1945 Apr 3 (Box 33, Folder 690)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1945 Apr 17 (Box 33, Folder 691)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1945 Apr 17 (Box 33, Folder 692)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1945 (Box 33, Folder 693)
      - Magazine writing, Unfinished article on: draft, typescript, corrected (Box 34, Folder 694)
      - "The Marches Always Pay": draft, typescript, carbon, 1936 (Box 34, Folder 695)
      - "Merry Christmas, All": draft, typescript, carbon, 1941 (Box 34, Folder 696)
      - "Mr. Moto Takes Them On": draft, typescript, carbon, 1942 (Box 34, Folder 697)
      - "My First Voyage"
        - Draft A, typescript and carbon (Box 34, Folder 698)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 699)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 700)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 701)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 702)
      - New England academies, Article on
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, 1949 Nov 3 (Box 34, Folder 703)
        - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 34, Folder 704)
      - "The New Look Reaches Boston"
        - Draft A, typescript, carbons, corrected, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 705)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbons (incomplete), 1952 (Box 34, Folder 706)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 707)
        - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 708)
      - Persia and trip around the world, Notes on: typescript, 1935 (Box 34, Folder 709)
      - "Poor Pan"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 710)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 711)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 712)
        - Draft D, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 713)
        - Draft D, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 714)
      - "Pozzi of Perugia"
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, 1924 (Box 34, Folder 715)
        - Correspondence, 1924 Jun 12 (Box 34, Folder 716)
      - "Return Trip to the Stone Age": draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 717)
      - "The Right Hand That Failed": draft, typescript, corrected (Box 34, Folder 718)
      - "The Road Turns Back"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 719)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 720)
      - "Roots": draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 721)
      - "Shirt Giver": draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 722)
      - Statement for Child Life for United China Relief: draft, typescript, carbon, 1942 Apr 6 (Box 35, Folder 723)
      - "Sugar and the Soul": draft, typescript, corrected (Box 35, Folder 724)
      - "Sun, Sea, and Sand"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 725)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, 1950 (Box 35, Folder 726)
      - "Taxi Dance": draft, typescript, carbon, 1942 (Box 35, Folder 727)
      - "Tell Me about the War"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 728)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 729)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 730)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 731)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 732)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 733)
      - "There Were Giants in Those Days"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1942 (Box 35, Folder 734)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1942 (Box 35, Folder 735)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, 1942 (Box 35, Folder 736)
      - "Tolerance"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1931 (Box 35, Folder 737)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1931 (Box 35, Folder 738)
        - Draft C, typescript, 1931 (Box 35, Folder 739)
      - Unidentified manuscripts
        - No. 1: draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 740)
        - No. 2: draft, typescript and holograph, corrected (Box 35, Folder 741)
        - No. 3: draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 742)
        - No. 4: draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 743)
        - No. 5: draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 744)
        - No. 6: draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 745)
        - No. 7: draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 746)
        - No. 8: draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 747)
        - No. 9: draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 748)
        - No. 10: draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 749)
      - Miscellaneous draft fragments, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 750)
    - Addresses, Lectures, and Speeches
      - Bates College lecture: draft, typescript, corrected, 1951 Oct 11 (Box 35, Folder 751)
      - Boston Book Fair lecture: draft, typescript, carbon, 1945 Oct 17 (Box 35, Folder 752)
      - Columbia University Club speech: draft, typescript, carbon, 1941 Mar 17 (Box 35, Folder 753)
      - "A Discussion of the Novel": draft, typescript, 1954 Jun 15 (Box 35, Folder 754)
      - "Do You Know the Brills?": draft, typescript, carbon, 1939 Apr 18 (Box 35, Folder 755)
      - Governor Dummer Academy speech: draft, typescript, carbon, 1939 Jun (Box 35, Folder 756)
      - Harvard University speeches
        - Class of 1915 thirty-fifth reunion dinner speech: draft, typescript, corrected, 1950 Jun 20 (Box 35, Folder 757)
        - Commencement address
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected and carbons, 1953 Jun 11 (Box 35, Folder 758)
          - Draft B, typescript and carbons, 1953 Jun 11 (Box 35, Folder 759)
          - Correspondence, 1953 Apr-May (Box 35, Folder 760)
        - Harvard School of Public Health address: draft, typescript, carbon, 1953 Jun 11 (Box 35, Folder 761)
        - "The Social Future of the Harvard Man in the Free World of Tomorrow"
          - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1948 (Box 35, Folder 762)
          - Draft B, typescript, carbon, 1948 (Box 35, Folder 763)
          - Draft C, typescript, carbon, 1948 (Box 35, Folder 764)
        - Unidentified speeches
          - No. 1: draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 765)
          - No. 1: draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 766)
          - No. 2: draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 767)
          - No. 2: draft B, typescript, carbons, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 768)
      - "In Retrospect" [Newburyport High School address]: draft, typescript, corrected, 1944 Jun (Box 36, Folder 769)
      - Lawrenceville School address: draft, typescript, corrected, 1943 Mar 16 (Box 36, Folder 770)
      - Pulitzer Prize speech
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 771)
        - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 772)
      - Sermon: draft, typescript, corrected, 1938 Jun 26 (Box 36, Folder 773)
      - "Some Rugged Individualists" [New England Society dinner]
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1939 Dec 21 (Box 36, Folder 774)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 775)
        - Galley proofs, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 776)
      - Tavern Club paper: draft, typescript and carbon, 1937 Nov 2 (Box 36, Folder 777)
      - Tuesday Night Club papers
        "Ascension Island"
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 778)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 779)
        - "The General": draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 780)
        - "Hollywood": draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 781)
        - "Honolulu, 1945"
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1945 Apr 22 (Box 36, Folder 782)
          - Draft A, typescript, carbon, 1945 Apr 22 (Box 36, Folder 783)
          - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 784)
          - Draft B, typescript, carbon, 1945 (Box 36, Folder 785)
        - "Sunday": draft, typescript, corrected (Box 36, Folder 786)
        - "When We Sailed on the Sloop John B"
          - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 787)
          - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 788)
          - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 789)
          - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 790)
        - "Where Are You, Prince?": draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 791)
        - Unidentified manuscripts
          - No. 1: draft, typescript, 1949 May (Box 36, Folder 792)
          - No. 1: draft, typescript, carbon, 1949 May (Box 36, Folder 793)
          - No. 2: draft, typescript, corrected, 1948 (Box 36, Folder 794)
          - No. 3: draft, typescript, corrected, 1947 (Box 36, Folder 795)
          - No. 4: draft, typescript, carbon, 1941 (Box 36, Folder 796)
      - University of Vermont speech [on "Construction of the Novel"]
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1949 Aug (Box 36, Folder 797)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1949 Aug (Box 36, Folder 798)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, 1949 Aug (Box 36, Folder 799)
        - Draft C, typescript, corrected, 1949 Aug (Box 36, Folder 800)
      - Unidentified speeches
        - No. 1: draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 801)
        - No. 2: draft, typescript, carbon, 1942 Jan 11 (Box 36, Folder 802)
        - No. 3: draft, typescript, corrected and carbon (Box 36, Folder 803)
        - No. 4: draft, typescript, corrected and carbon (Box 36, Folder 804)
    - Book Reviews
      - Bacon, Leonard, Semi-Centennial: draft, typescript, carbon, 1939 (Box 36, Folder 805)
      - Bromfield, Louis, It Takes All Kinds
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 806)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 807)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 808)
      - Canfield, Dorothy, Seasoned Timber: draft, typescript, carbon, 1939 (Box 36, Folder 809)
      - Heyerdahl, Thor, The Secret of Easter Island: printed version (Box 36, Folder 809a)
      - Hindus, Maurice, Sons and Fathers: draft, typescript, carbon (Box 36, Folder 810)
      - Howe, M. A. DeWolfe, A Venture in Remembrance
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 811)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 812)
      - Hughes, Rupert, Stately Timber
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, 1939 (Box 36, Folder 813)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, 1939 (Box 36, Folder 814)
        - Correspondence, 1939 Feb 7 (Box 36, Folder 815)
      - Hunt, George P., Coral Comes High: draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 816)
      - Jenkins, Elizabeth, Elizabeth the Great: printed version (incomplete), 1959 (Box 36, Folder 816a)
      - Knauth, Percy, Germany in Defeat: draft, typescript (Box 36, Folder 817)
      - Mackay, Margaret M., Lady with Jade: draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 818)
      - McIntire, Marguerite, Free and Clear: draft, typescript, carbon (Box 37, Folder 819)
      - Mauldin, Bill, Up Front: draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 820)
      - Morley, Christopher, Kitty Foyle: draft, typescript, carbon, 1939 (Box 37, Folder 821)
      - Wallop, Douglass, The Year the Yankees Lost the Pennant: draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 822)
    - Letters to the Editor
      - Letters to the Editor, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 823)
    - Contributions to Works of Others
      - "Foreword" to book by Heinz Rettig
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 824)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 825)
      - "Introduction" to Drive by Charles Codman
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 826)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 827)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 828)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 829)
        - Draft D, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 830)
        - Draft D, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 831)
        - Galley proofs, 1949 (Box 37, Folder 831a)
        - Galley proofs, corrected, 1949 (Box 37, Folder 832)
        - "Afterword" by Bernard S. Carter: draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 833)
- Brandt & Brandt Papers, 1922-70; Series II; 2.5; (6 boxes)
  The Brandt & Brandt Papers contain business correspondence, synopses, printed versions, book reviews, publicity, and advertisements of Marquand's writings, bibliographical material, biographical material, photographic negatives, and works on Marquand.
  - BUSINESS CORRESPONDENCE
    - Business correspondence, 1948-52 (Box 38, Folder 834-55)
    - Business correspondence, 1953-56 (Box 39, Folder 856-74)
    - Business correspondence, 1956-57 (Box 40, Folder 875-93)
    - Business correspondence, 1958-62 (Box 41, Folder 894-918)
    - Business correspondence, 1963-70 (Box 42, Folder 919-36)
  - WRITINGS
    - Books
      - B. F.'s Daughter: book reviews, 1946 (Box 42, Folder 937)
      - Castle Sinister: synopsis, draft, typescript, photocopy, 1938 Feb 12 (Box 42, Folder 938)
        See also: Oversize, Box 50, folder 1089
      - Do Tell Me, Doctor Johnson
        See: Oversize, Box 50, folder 1090
      - Don't Ask Questions
        See: Oversize, Box 50, folder 1091
      - H. M. Pulham, Esquire: book reviews, 1941 Feb (Box 42, Folder 938a)
      - It's Loaded, Mr. Bauer
        See: Oversize, Box 50, folders 1092-93
      - The Late George Apley: publicity, 1937 Jan 9 (Box 42, Folder 939)
      - Ming Yellow: synopsis, draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 940)
      - Sincerely, Willis Wayde: synopsis, printed version, 1955 Mar (Box 42, Folder 941)
      - So Little Time
        - Synopsis, draft, typescript, corrected, 1943 May 15 (Box 42, Folder 942)
        - Advertisements, 1943 Aug 21 (Box 42, Folder 942a)
        - Book reviews, 1943 Aug 21 (Box 42, Folder 942b)
      - Stopover: Tokyo: advertisements, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 942c)
      - Timothy Dexter Revisted
        - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 943)
        - Book reviews, 1960 Sep (Box 42, Folder 944)
      - The Unspeakable Gentleman
        - Synopsis, draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 945)
        - Book review, typescript, corrected, 1922 Jul 28 (Box 42, Folder 946)
      - Wickford Point
        See also: Oversize, Box 50, folder 1094
        - Synopsis, draft, typescript, 1939 Jan 18 (Box 42, Folder 947)
        - Book reviews, 1939 Mar 18 (Box 42, Folder 947a)
      - Winner Take All
        See: Oversize, Box 50, folder 1095
      - Women and Thomas Harrow
        See also: Oversize, Box 50, folders 1096-97
        - Advertisements, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 947b)
        - Book reviews, 1958-59 (Box 42, Folder 948)
    - Shorter Works: Essays and Short Stories
      See also: Oversize, Boxes 50-51, folders 1098-155
      - "Back Pay," American: printed version, 1934 Aug (Box 42, Folder 949)
      - "Courtesy of the Port," Good Housekeeping: printed version with synopsis, 1957 Feb, Aug (Box 42, Folder 950)
      - "Goodbye, Piccadilly," Good Housekeeping
        - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 951)
        - Printed version, 1955 Jul (Box 42, Folder 952)
      - "I Heard an Old Man Say," Good Housekeeping: printed version, 1943 Oct (Box 42, Folder 953)
      - "The Island," Good Housekeeping: printed version, 1943 Sep (Box 42, Folder 954)
      - "She Was Always a Swell Girl," Good Housekeeping: printed version, 1941 Dec (Box 42, Folder 955)
      - "Sun, Sea, and Sand," Cosmopolitan: printed version, 1950 May (Box 42, Folder 956)
  - OTHER PAPERS
    - Bibliographical material
      - Bibliographical material, 1949-69, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 957-60)
    - Biographical material
      - Biographical sketches, 1937-46, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 961-62)
      - Obituaries, 1960 Jul (Box 43, Folder 963)
    - Photographic negatives
      - Photographic negatives, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 964)
    - Works on Marquand
      - Bond, Alice Dixon, "New England Literary Tour: Marquand's Kent Island House Visited," Boston Herald: printed version, 1942 Jul 15 (Box 43, Folder 965)
      - Burlingame, Roger, "John Marquand," printed version (Box 43, Folder 965a)
      - Driver, Josephine P., "The Young John Marquand," The Atlantic Monthly: printed version (Box 43, Folder 965b)
      - Fleming, Thomas, "Speaking of Books: The Novelist as Journalist," The New York Times Book Review: printed version, 1968 Jul 21 (Box 43, Folder 965c)
      - Frankelin, Stanley, "John P. Marquand in Kitale," The Sunday Post (Kenya): printed version, 1959 Aug 16 (Box 43, Folder 965)
      - Hackett, Walter, "Marquand's Novels Come to Life in Newburyport," The New York Times: printed version, 1969 Sep 28 (Box 43, Folder 965e)
      - Hamburger, Philip, "There's No Place," The New Yorker: printed version, 1952 (Box 43, Folder 966)
      - "Harvard Is Too Big for Marquand," Boston Post: printed version, 1939 Mar 24 (Box 43, Folder 967)
      - Hutchens, John K., "People Who Read and Write," The New York Times Book Review: printed version, 1936 May 19 (Box 43, Folder 968)
      - Jones, Howard Mumford, "The Gradual Emergence of John P. Marquand," The Saturday Review: printed version, 1943 Aug 21 (Box 43, Folder 968a)
      - Prim, Mary Elizabeth, "Marquand Martyred at Autograph Party," Boston Transcript: printed version, 1939 Mar 23 (Box 43, Folder 969)
      - Van Gelder, Robert, "Marquand Unburdens Himself," The New York Times Book Review: printed version, 1940 Apr 7 (Box 43, Folder 970)
      - Smith, William James, "J. P. Marquand, Esq.," Commonweal: printed version, photocopy, 1958 Nov 7 (Box 43, Folder 971)
      - Weeks, Edward, "John P. Marquand," The Atlantic Monthly: printed version (Box 43, Folder 971a)
- Stephen Birmingham Papers, 1930-73; Series III; 2.52; (7 boxes)
  The Stephen Birmingham Papers contain research files, interviews, manuscript drafts, book reviews, fan mail, photographs, and business correspondence relating to The Late John Marquand.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 52 contains audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - RESEARCH MATERIAL
    - List of Contents
      - List of contents, 1972 Sep (Box 44, Folder 972)
    - Research Files
      - Auchincloss, Louis S.
        See: Box 45, folder 998
      - Baumgarten, Bernice
        See: Box 44, folders 988 and 989
      - Benjamin, Ben
        See: Box 45, folders 1005 and 1009; Box 49, folder 1073b
      - Birmingham, Stephen
        See: Box 44, folders 994-97; Box 45, folders 998-99, and 1011
      - Book-of-the-Month Club, 1959 Jun-Jul (Box 44, Folder 973)
      - Blanchard, Charles B.
        See: Box 44, folders 990-91
      - Brandt, Carl (Box 44, Folder 974)
        See also: Box 44, folder 975-77, and 990; Box 45, folders 1004-05, 1007, and 1009-10
      - Brandt, Carol, 1942-68, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 975-76)
        See also: Box 44, folders 974, 977, 991, 994, and 996; Box 45, folders 998-99, 1002, 1007, and 1010-11
      - Brandt & Brandt, 1951-73 (Box 44, Folder 977)
      - Dennis, Rodney G.
        See: Box 44, folder 995; Box 49, folder 1087
      - Everitt, Raymond
        See: Box 44, folder 988; Box 45, folder 1002
      - Fadiman, Clifton
        See: Box 44, folder 995; Box 45, folder 998
      - Fiske, Constance ("Conney") M.
        See also: Box 44, folders 994, and 996-97; Box 45, folders 998-99; Box 49, folders 1073c and 1086-88
        Articles on Marquand
        - "Battery A at the Border," Yankee: printed version, 1968 Jun (Box 44, Folder 978)
        - "John P. Marquand: ' Something of an Apley Himself ,'" The Saturday Review: printed version, photocopy, 1938 Dec 10 (Box 44, Folder 979)
        - "Treasure Island with John Marquand": typescript, photocopy (Box 44, Folder 980)
        - Correspondence, 1930-70, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 981-82)
        - Notes, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 983)
      - Gallup, Donald
        See: Box 44, folder 977; Box 45, folder 999
      - Greene, Joseph I.
        See: Box 44, folder 975
      - Griffenberg, E. Dickinson, Jr.: "John P. Marquand: For the Hollow Men New Stuffing," honors thesis, Williams College, Williamstown, Mass.: type- script, photocopy, 1952 May (Box 44, Folder 984)
        See also: Box 45, folder 998; Box 49, folder 1073e
      - Hale, Robert, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 985)
        See also: Box 44, folder 987
      - Hall, John M.
        See: Box 44, folder 987
      - Heit, Albert
        See: Box 45, folders 1007 and 1009
      - Hellman, Lillian, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 986)
        See also: Box 49, folder 1073c
      - Kahler, Hugh MacNair
        See: Box 44, folder 990; Box 45, folder 1007
      - Lindbergh, Charles A. and Anne Morrow
        See: Box 44, folder 992; Box 45, folders 998-99
      - Little, Brown & Company, 1938-61 (Box 44, Folder 987-91)
      - McIntyre, Alfred R.
        See: Box 44, folders 987-89
      - Mansfield, Luther S.
        See: Box 45, folder 999
      - Marquand, Adelaide, 1963-71, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 992)
        See also: Box 44, folders 976 and 988
      - Marquand, John P.
        See also: Box 44, folders 973, 975-77, 981-82, 987-91, and 993-94
        - General correspondence, 1957-69 (Box 44, Folder 993-97)
        - General correspondence, 1970-71, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 998-99)